Franz Boas Professional Papers ca.1860-1942 Mss.B.B61p
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Professional Papers, ca.1860-1942; Collection II; 12.5 linear feet
  - Chamberlain, Alexander F. Review of Chamberlain's Kootenai language manuscript (Box 18)
  - Chavez, Ezequiel A. (Box 18)
  - Coeur d'Alene Indian Text (Box 18)
  - Cohen, Marcel (Box 18)
  - Cohen, Morris R. (Box 18)
  - Collier, John (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - Anthropology Department - Budgets (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - Anthropology Department - Plan for Seminar, 1905-06 (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - Courses of Instruction in Anthropology (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - Library (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - List of specimens placed to order, Jan. 1909 (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - Plan for Research on Economic Imperialism (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - School of Sanitary Science and Public Health (Box 19)
  - Columbia University - Special Committee on Advanced Research Work, 1915 (Box 19)
  - Comer, George (Box 19)
  - Committee for Organization of International Congress of Anthropological Sciences, 1912 (Box 19)
  - Committee on Collections from Eastern Asia - Minutes, 1901 - 1905; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Committee on North American Indian Languages (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - "American Linguistics" by C. F. Voegelin, [1937] (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - Financial records (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - "Opinions on work in American Linguistics," by Gladys S. Reichard, [1937] (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - "Outline of the History of American Linguistics," by A. L. Kroeber, [1937] (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - "Philosophical Aspects of Language," c. 1937 by Leonard Bloomfield (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - Publications & work supported by (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - Report, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - Report, 1941 (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - Report & Financial Statements, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - Report of Conference, April 25-26, 1937; 6 folders (Box 19)
  - Committee on Research in American Native Languages - "Training needs for students of American Indian Linguistics," - by Ed Sapir, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (Box 19)
  - Cranmer, Dan (Box 19)
  - Crolly, Charles Stewart (Box 19)
  - Czeranouslir, Jan? (Box 19)
  - Dakota Indians - "The story of the beginning as told in the Wakan Wacipi of Dakota" (Box 19)
  - Davalos, Dalbino (Box 19)
  - Deloria, Ella (Box 19)
  - Deloria, Ella. Report for Dr. Boas, re: Capitalism and the Dakota-Sioux (Box 19)
  - Dewey, John (Box 19)
  - Diercks, Gustav (Box 19)
  - Dillon, Mrs. Hortense (Box 19)
  - "Distribution of Mental Diseases and Assimilation" (Box 19)
  - Dixon, Roland B. (Box 19)
  - Donaldson, Henry H. (Box 19)
  - Dorsey, George A. (Box 19)
  - Dorsey, James Owen. Extract of address on "The Biloxi Indians of Louisiana", 1893 (Box 19)
  - Dunn, J. P. (Box 19)
  - East Asiatic Committee (Box 19)
  - Efron, David (Box 19)
  - Efron, David. Material for Gesture and Environment, 1941; 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Ellis, Grace Kirtland (Box 19)
  - Emergency Society for German and Austrian Science and Art (Box 19)
  - Emergency Society in Aid of European Science and Art (Box 19)
  - Engerrand, Jorge C. (Box 19)
  - Ernst, A. Henson (Box 19)
  - Eskimo Illustrations (Box 19)
  - Fahns, H. (Box 20)
  - Fansler, D. S. (Box 20)
  - Farrand, Livingston? (Box 20)
  - Ferrero-Sallitto Defense Committee (Box 20)
  - Fewkes, J. Walter (Box 20)
  - Finkelstein, Moses I. (Box 20)
  - Fondo de Cultura Economica (Box 20)
  - Foreign service - Educational preparation (Box 20)
  - Fortune, Reo F. (Box 20)
  - Frachtenberg, Leo J. (Box 20)
  - Frelinghuysen, Joseph S. (Box 20)
  - Friends of Franz Boas, 1942 (Box 20)
  - Gamio, Manuel. Review of an article by Gamio (Box 20)
  - German American Emergency Conference (Box 20)
  - Germanistic Society of America (Box 20)
  - Gissler, Carl Fridrich (Box 20)
  - Goldenweiser, A. A. (Box 20)
  - Gordon, E. M. (Box 20)
  - Grunwedel, Albert (Box 20)
  - Gulkowitsch, Lazar (Box 20)
  - Haddon, A. C. (Box 20)
  - Hahn, Frida (Box 20)
  - Haile, Bernard (Box 20)
  - Haller, Ludwig (Box 20)
  - Hancock, J. A. (Box 20)
  - Hanover, Germany (Box 20)
  - Harris, W. F. (Box 20)
  - Harrow, Benjamin (Box 20)
  - Henry, Jules? (Box 20)
  - Herzog, George (Box 20)
  - Hewett, Edgar L. (Box 20)
  - Heye, George G. (Box 20)
  - Hodge, William (Box 20)
  - Hodges, N. D. C. (Box 20)
  - Holmes, William Henry (Box 20)
  - Honey, James A. Letter to George H. Chase (Box 20)
  - Hooton, Earnest A. "Plain Statements about Race" (Box 20)
  - Horsford, Cornelia (Box 20)
  - H. O. Houghton & Co. (Box 20)
  - Hunt, George - Kwakiutl material, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Hunt, George - Kwakiutl notebook (Box 22)
  - Hunt, George - Receipt (Box 20)
  - Immigration Legislation (Box 20)
  - Instituto Mexicano De Investigaciones Linguisticas (Box 20)
  - Instituto Politecnico Nacional, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - International Archeologic and Ethnologic Commission (Box 20)
  - International Congress of American Democracies (Box 20)
  - International Journal of American Linguistics - Accounts, 1929-1934 (Box 20)
  - International Journal of American Linguistics - Manuscripts (Box 20)
  - International Journal of American Linguistics - Subscribers (Box 20)
  - Jacobi, Abraham (Box 20)
  - Jacobs, Melville (Box 20)
  - James, Goldye L. (Mrs.) (Box 20)
  - James, J. B., Jr. (Box 20)
  - Japanese American Committee for Democracy (Box 20)
  - Jastrow, Joseph (Box 20)
  - Jenks, Albert Ernest (Box 20)
  - Jesup, Morris K. (Box 20)
  - Jesup Siberian Expedition (Box 20)
  - Jesup Siberian Expedition - Expenses (Box 20)
  - Joseph, Nathan & Co., San Francisco (Box 20)
  - Kaufmann, Max (Box 20)
  - Klein, Jerome (Box 20)
  - Klineburg, Otto et al. "Problem of Selective Migration" (Box 20)
  - Krehbiel, Henry E. (Box 20)
  - Kroeber, A. L. (Box 20)
  - Kroeber, A. L. "Outline of the History of American Linguistics" (Box 20)
    See: Committee on Research in American Native Languages - " Outline of the History of American Linguistics," by A. L. Kroeber.
  - Krug, [Florian]? - "The Tortoise and the Elephant" (Box 20)
  - Kwakiutl material (Box 20)
  - Laidlaw, G. E. (Box 20)
  - Lansing, Robert (Box 20)
  - Laufer, Berthold (Box 20)
  - Lehmann, Hedwig Boas - Reminiscences of Franz Boas (Box 20)
  - Lehmann, Rudolph (Box 20)
  - Lehmann, Walter (Box 20)
  - Lenz, Charlotty H. (Box 20)
  - Lesser, Alexander (Box 20)
  - Lincer, William (Box 20)
  - Lindemann, M. "Dr. Boas, Baffinland" (Box 20)
  - Literary Institute of Yucatan (Box 20)
  - Llewellyn, Karl N. (Box 20)
  - Loomis, Gertrude Shepperle (Box 20)
  - Lowie, Robert H. (Box 20)
  - Lowman, Guy S., Jr. (Box 20)
  - von Luschan (Box 20)
  - McAneny, George (Box 20)
  - MacCurdy, George Grant (Box 20)
  - McGee, W. (Box 20)
  - MacLean, Malcolm S. - "Negro Higher Education" (Box 20)
  - Marini, Myra (Box 20)
  - Marsh, Gordon (Box 20)
  - Marshall, Louis. "On the importance of comparative anthropology in New York City", 1926 (Box 20)
  - Martine, James E. (Box 20)
  - Mason, J. Alden (Box 20)
  - Mason, J. Alden - List of objects (Box 20)
  - Mayer, Theresa (Box 20)
  - Mayo-Smith, Richmond (Box 20)
  - Mechling, William H. (Box 20)
  - Meier, Joseph (Box 20)
  - Meillet, C. (Box 20)
  - Merriam, C. Hart (Box 20)
  - Mexican Cooperation Society (Box 20)
  - Mexico - Plan for organizing a school of Archaeology (Box 20)
  - Meyer, Jacob - Estate (Box 20)
  - Meyer, Jacob - Will (Box 20)
  - Meyer, Willy (Box 20)
  - Michelson, Nicholas (Nikolai) (Box 20)
  - Michelson, Truman (Box 20)
  - Mitscherlich, Waldemar (Box 20)
  - Moore, Jane Newell (Box 20)
  - Morf, Heinrich - "Civitas Dei" (Box 20)
  - Morgan, Edith (Box 20)
  - Murphy, Gardner (Box 20)
  - Muller, Karl (Box 20)
  - Murrell, Mitchell (Box 20)
  - Mutch, James S. (Box 20)
  - National Committee for Defense of Political Prisoners (Box 20)
  - National Emergency Conference (Box 20)
  - Newell, W. W. (Box 20)
  - Newman, Stanley S. (Box 20)
  - Nicodemus, Julia Theresa (Box 20)
  - Norsemthy, Naomi (Box 20)
  - Nsibirwa, Manteni L. (Box 20)
  - Nuttall, Zelia (Box 20)
  - Olbrechts, Franz M. (Box 20)
  - Osgood, H. L. (Box 20)
  - Parsons, Elsie Clews (Box 20)
  - Peabody, George to Elsie C. Parsons (Box 20)
  - Penck, Albrecht (Box 20)
  - Photographs (Box 20)
  - Pilsudski, Bronislav (Box 20)
  - Plandinette, J. (Box 20)
  - Plimpton, George H. (Box 20)
  - Poetry (Box 20)
  - Population studies - Proposals for study of the "Quality of a Population", 1937 (Box 20)
  - Powell, Thomas Reed (Box 20)
  - "Preservation of historic and prehistoric ruins, monuments, archaeological objects and other antiquities" (Box 20)
  - Prince, J. D. (Box 20)
  - Putnam, F. W. (Box 20)
  - Quain, B. H. "The differential leukocyte count" (Box 21)
  - Radin, Paul (Box 21)
  - Reichard, Gladys (Box 21)
  - Reichard, Gladys, 1923-1942 (Box 21)
  - Reichard, Gladys. Letters from German Friends, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Reichard, Gladys. "Opinion on work in American Linguistics" (Box 21)
    See: Committee on Research in American Native Languages - " Opinions on work in American Linguistics," by Gladys S. Reichard
  - Reko, Victor A. (Box 21)
  - Report of Committee in Charge of Yale-Columbia Courses for Foreign Service (Box 21)
  - Richard, Ernst (Box 21)
  - Rivet, Paul. "Les Melaneso Polynesiens et Les Australiens", c. 1924 (Box 21)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. Declaration of War on Germany, with Boas' comments (Box 21)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel (Box 21)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel. Notes for biography of Franz Boas (Box 21)
  - S., Professor (Box 21)
  - Sapir, Edward (Box 21)
  - Sapir, Edward - Committee on Research in American Native Languages (Box 21)
  - Sargent, Homer E. (Box 21)
  - Schiff, Jacob H. - American Museum Fund (Box 21)
  - Schreiber, Witold (Box 21)
  - Schultz, R. R. (Box 21)
  - "The Scientist Recognizes No Basic Differences Among Races" (Box 21)
  - Seaver, Jay W. (Box 21)
  - Seler, Eduardo (Box 21)
  - Seytter, Emil (Box 21)
  - Shelby, Gertrude Matthews (Box 21)
  - Skillings, E. "Intellectual Famine Relief for Central Europe", ca. 1920 (Box 21)
  - Smith, Edwin S. "Democracy and Academic Freedom", 1941 (Box 21)
  - Snyder, Louis L. (Box 21)
  - Sock, Paul (Box 21)
  - Spain (Box 21)
  - Speers, Mary W. H. (Box 21)
  - Spier, Leslie (Box 21)
  - Spinden, Herbert J. (Box 21)
  - Steinen, Diether von den (Box 21)
  - Steinen, Karl von den (Box 21)
  - Stevenson, Mrs. Cornelius (Box 21)
  - Sturtevant, E. H. (Box 21)
  - Swanton, John R. (Box 21)
  - Symposium in the Intellectual Foundation of Social Change (Box 21)
  - Termer, Franz (Box 21)
  - Thalbitzer, William (Box 21)
  - Thilenius, G. (Box 21)
  - Thomas, W. I. (Box 21)
  - Thorndike, E. L. (Box 21)
  - "Tonkawa Phonetics" (Box 21)
  - Tozzer, Alfred W. (Box 21)
  - Umlauff, Gustave (Box 21)
  - United States v. Tatos Cartozian, 1924-1925; 5 folders (Box 21)
  - United States. Senate - Bill defining a "white person", 1926 (Box 21)
  - Urbach, Braverei Julius (Box 21)
  - Urbach, Braverei Julius - Estate/Business, 1910 (Box 21)
  - Voegelin, Carl F. "American Linguistics" (Box 21)
    See: Committee on Research in American Native Languages - " American Linguistics" by C. F. Voegelin
  - Vogeler, Adolph, [1877] (Box 21)
  - Wagner, Max Leopold (Box 21)
  - Wallis, [Wilson, D.]? (Box 21)
  - Waterman, T. T. (Box 21)
  - Weike, Wilhelm (Box 21)
  - Weike, Wilhelm - Diary, 1883 June-1884 September (Box 22)
    Baffinland notebooks with sketches, letters, maps.
  - Williams & Wilkins Co. (Box 21)
  - Willoughly, Charles C. (Box 21)
  - World's Columbian Exposition - Anthropology Building Floorplan (Box 21)
  - World War I - Boas letters in opposition (Box 21)
  - Yampolsky, Cecil and Helen (Box 21)
  - Yampolsky, Helene Boas. Boas Papers Project, c. 1960 (Box 21)
  - Yampolsky, Helene Boas. "Excerpts from Letter Diary of Franz Boas on his First Field Trip to Northwest Coast" (Box 21)
  - Yarnall, Stanley R. (Box 21)